Brandon K Buchs

Grovetown, GA 30813 | 623.889.4180 | brandon.k.buchs@gmail.com | brandonkbuchs.github.io

MULTI-DISCIPLINED LANGUAGE ANALYST

Highly organized and committed professional with 12 years of experience in fulfilling all steps in the intelligence cycle to contribute to efficient, effective, and enduring operations. Collaborative across all departmental levels to build consensus, track achievement, and troubleshoot emerging issues.

- Core Competencies -

- Pashto Language Translation
- Oral and Written Communication
- Leadership

- Intelligence Analysis
- Spatial Analysis
- Positive teamwork and collaboration

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

United States Army Fort Gordon, GA

Multi Disciplined Language Analyst (June 2018-Present)

Combine language and geospatial analysis skills with military experience to inform customers across the globe of adversary intentions. Manage three teammates to increase efficiency across organization.

United States Army Fort Gordon, GA

Command Language Program Manager (January 2017 – June 2018)

Meet training, testing, and language proficiency development needs for more than 200 language analysts working 13 different languages. Improved overall language proficiency scores by more than 40% across the organization. Crafted language policy and guidance for the Army and Department of Defense.

United States Army Fort Gordon, GA

Division Manager (October 2015 – January 2017)

Oversaw the daily operations for more than 250 personnel. Ensured accountability of personnel and equipment to maintain continuity of sensitive 24/7/365 intelligence operations.

EDUCATION

Arizona State University Tempe, AZ

Bachelor of Science in Planning in Urban Planning (December 2017) GPA 4.00

Defense Language Institute Foreign Language Center Monterey, CA

Associate of Arts in Pashto-Afghan Language (May 2015) GPA 4.00, Provost Marshall's Award